nordictrack.com 2018-11-25

# Privacy Policy | NordicTrack

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which ICON Health & Fitness, Inc. (together with its affiliates, partners, licensors, subsidiaries, and/or related companies, “Company,” “we,” “us,” “our”) collect, use, maintain, and disclose information collected from and about you and other users (“you” or “User”) while using the ICON Health & Fitness websites, including without limitation [www.iconfitness.com](https://www.iconfitness.com/), [www.ifit.com](https://www.ifit.com/), [www.nordictrack.com](https://www.nordictrack.com/), [www.altrarunning.com](https://www.altrarunning.com/), [www.proform.com](https://www.proform.com/), [www.freemotionfitness.com](https://home.freemotionfitness.com/), [www.weiderfitness.com](https://www.weiderfitness.com/), [www.weslo.com](https://www.weslo.com/), [www.healthrider.com](https://www.healthrider.com/), [www.getgoldsgym.com](https://www.getgoldsgym.com/), [www.workoutwarehouse.com](https://www.workoutwarehouse.com/), and [my.iconfitness.com](https://my.iconfitness.com/) (each an “ICON Site,” and collectively, the “ICON Sites”), and the services provided on the ICON Sites, including iFit Services (each an “ICON Service” and collectively, “ICON Services”) whether accessed via the Internet, a mobile device, other electronic devices, or by any other means. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made a part of the Terms of Use governing use of the ICON Sites and ICON Services. We are dedicated to safeguarding Personally Identifiable Information (as defined below) that we collect. 

We store the information we collect in the United States, so if you are accessing an ICON Site from another country, your information is being transferred to and from the United States. 

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHEN

Some of the information we collect from Users of the ICON Sites can be used to identify the User and some cannot. For example, we collect from Users of the ICON Sites (1) “Personally Identifiable Information” which is information that can be used to locate you, contact you, or determine your specific identity (such as name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, user name, credit card information, etc.) and (2) “aggregate information” which is information about your activities on an ICON Site or in connection with an ICON Service that cannot be used to identify, locate, or contact you (such as frequency of visits to ICON Sites, data entered when using ICON Sites, ICON Site pages most frequently accessed, browser type, links a User clicks, IP address, and other similar information). 

WE COLLECT INFORMATION FROM YOU: 
  * When you use a credit card to pay for any of our services or products, we ask for your name, address, credit card and credit card-related information.
  * Once you have created an account, you may complete your profile by providing additional Personally Identifiable Information about yourself.
  * When you connect your ICON Site account with your Facebook account or other social media account we will have access to the publicly available information from your Facebook or other social media page, and Facebook or other social media site will have access to information you log through an ICON Site while logged onto your ICON Site account through Facebook or the other social media site.
  * When you enter a contest, sweepstakes or promotion through an ICON Site.
  * When you submit comments, feedback, or suggestions through an ICON Site.
  * When you visit an ICON Site, even if you are not logged in, we gather information about your computer operating system (e.g., Windows XP or Mac OS), your “IP Address,” the web browser (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer) being used, the referring website information, usage data regarding your activity on such ICON Site, including what web pages you visit or share, what functions you use, as well as overall time spent on that ICON Site. We use this data for internal analysis about the ICON Sites’ performance and services.
  * When you share your content with family and friends using ICON’s products, send gift certificates and products, or invite others to participate in an ICON Service or forum, we may collect the information you provide about those people such as name, mailing address, email address, and phone number. We will use such information to fulfill your requests and provide the relevant product or service.

You can refuse to supply Personally Identifiable Information, but it may prevent you from having access to an ICON Site’s full functionality. The ICON Sites allow you to edit and update your personal information and preferences at any time. Once you have created an account and log in to an ICON Site -- you are not anonymous to us. 

The ICON Sites are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on the ICON Sites or on or through any of the ICON Services or features, make any purchases through the ICON Sites, use any of the interactive or public comment features of the ICON Sites or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13 years of age, please contact us at the contact information provided below. 

### How we use collected information

We collect and use your Personally Identifiable Information for the following purposes: 

To personalize user experience: 

  * We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use ICON Services and resources provided on the ICON Sites.

To improve the ICON Sites and your User experience: 
  * We continually strive to improve our offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
  * We may use information we gather about you to display data trends based on different demographics, make offers and discounts available to you, among other things.

To provide customer service: 
  * Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.
  * When a User submits questions or comments to us, we may use that information to respond to the User.
  * By creating an account with us, you agree that we may contact you by phone, email, mail, or text message to respond to questions that you submit to us.

To process transactions: 
  * We may use the information Users provide when placing an order only to process that order. We do not share credit card information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service or in connection with our transfer or assignment of our right to payment as permitted by the Terms of Use.

To send periodic emails and printed materials: 
  * The address and email address Users provide will be used to send them information, sales offers, and updates pertaining to their ICON Services. Such addresses may also be used to respond to Users, and/or other requests or questions. By creating an account on an ICON Site, Users are opting-in to our mailing list, and will receive emails and/or mail that may include company news, updates, sales information, related product or service information, etc. We may send offers and communications to Users after any subscription or membership to an ICON Service has concluded. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails or mail, they may do so by contacting us via the “unsubscribe” link on an ICON Site.

For our marketing purposes: 
  * We may use the information Users provide to display targeted advertising or other content that we think may be of interest to the User based on information the User has shared with us.
  * We may provide data mining services to third-parties interested in better understanding our Users such as aggregate information about the ICON Sites’ user base, including interests, purchases made, so that such parties may determine if they would like to advertise to our Users.
  * By registering an account, you agree that we may contact you at the phone number you have provided us, even if your number is on a do-not-call list or a wireless number, for our marketing purposes.
  * We may connect and link your information with the information provided by you to any ICON Site.

We may also use or sell aggregate information such as information about the pages visited to improve the design, content and performance of the ICON Sites, or to analyze usage and the popularity of certain pages of the ICON Sites. 

### International Transfers of Personal Information/Safe Harbor Statement

As part of our international operations, we may transfer data to our servers and affiliates in other countries from time to time for our legitimate business purposes and to provide services to you. 

_

### Financial Information

_

When you purchase our services, you will be asked to provide credit card and/or billing information and email address. When credit card data is entered into our system, it is immediately tokenized and sent to a secure payment processor. Your credit card information cannot be seen by our agents and is never stored in our systems. We will use the information provided in connection with a User’s purchase to process your order and for no other purpose. 

### WHEN WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may provide Personally Identifiable Information to our authorized service providers who assist us in providing ICON Services and performing functions on our behalf. They are prevented from using it in any other way. 

We may share, rent, sell, or lease, your personal contact information to our trusted marketing partners for their internal or commercial purposes. 

We will disclose information we maintain when required by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may disclose such information in response to requests from law enforcement agencies or other public agencies if we feel that such disclosure may prevent the instigation of a crime. In addition, we may sell or otherwise disclose to third-parties information that does not constitute Personally Identifiable Information. 

Finally, we may disclose your information if (i) there is a transfer, assignment, or sale of our assets or ownership in connection with a proposed or consummated corporate reorganization, such as a merger or acquisition, to the extent permitted by law, or (ii) upon assignment of your membership or Membership Fees to a third-party as permitted by the Terms of Use. 

### WEB BROWSER COOKIES AND OTHER TECHNOLOGIES USED TO COLLECT INFORMATION

In addition to the collection of information described above, we use various technologies to collect information from your computer and about your activities on the ICON Sites. 

  * Cookies. When you visit an ICON Site, we may assign your computer one or more cookies, to facilitate access to such ICON Site and to personalize your experience on that ICON Site. A cookie is a small text file, with no Personally Identifiable Information, that we place on User’s computer browser. Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on an ICON Site, such as the web pages you visit and the links you click. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on the ICON Sites.
  * Other technologies. We may use standard Internet technology, such as web beacons and other similar technologies, to track your use of the ICON Sites. Web beacons are tiny graphics which are embedded in the webpage and are used for similar purposes as cookies to track activity. We also may include web beacons in e-mail messages or newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize the services we offer to visitors of the ICON Sites, to deliver targeted advertisements, and to measure the overall effectiveness of our online advertising, content, programming or other activities.
  * Information collected by third-parties. We may allow third-parties, including our authorized service providers, advertising companies, and ad networks, to display advertisements on the ICON Sites. These companies may use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to collect information about users who view or interact with their advertisements. The ICON Sites do not provide any personal information to these third-parties. This information allows them to deliver targeted advertisements and gauge their effectiveness.

### HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on the ICON Sites. 

Sensitive and private data exchange between an ICON Site and a User happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected with digital signatures. 

We want you to feel confident using the ICON Sites. However, no system can be completely secure. Therefore, although we take steps to secure your information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, searches, or other communications will always remain secure. Users should also take care with how they handle and disclose their personal information and should avoid sending personal information through insecure email. Please refer to the Federal Trade Commission’s website at http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/menus/consumer/data.shtm for information about how to protect yourself against identity theft. 

### DELETING YOUR INFORMATION

If you have cancelled your account with an Icon Site or Icon Service, and wish to delete your account information, please contact us at (866) 608-1798 during regular business hours. If we delete your account, your user profile will no longer be visible and all information associated with your account will be permanently deleted. We may retain and use your information to comply with applicable law, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements. You may still receive promotional emails from us regarding new Icon Products or Icon Services. 

### THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

Users may find advertising or other content on the ICON Sites that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the ICON Sites. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to an ICON Site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies. 

### ADVERTISING DISCLAIMER

We share no affiliation with any political party or its views. Our ads visible on political websites are there as a result of remarketing, not a partnership, affiliation, or endorsement. 

Remarketing lets us show ads to people who have visited the ICON Sites. When people leave an ICON Site without buying anything, remarketing helps us reconnect with them by showing relevant ads across their different devices and websites. The ads simply follow the user to the sites they visit. 

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to update and change this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to you. 

We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy periodically and become aware of modifications. 

### YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THESE TERMS

By using an ICON Site, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the ICON Sites. Your continued use of an ICON Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes. 

### CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of the ICON Sites that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. 

### CONTACTING US

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the ICON Sites, or your dealings with the ICON Sites, please contact us at: 

1-800-862-3348  
c/o Privacy Manager  
1500 South 1000 West  
Logan, Utah 84321  
service@iconfitness.com

## Shipping Policy

All non-UPS shipments require a customer signature upon delivery. The shipping company will call before attempting to deliver your machine. A total of three attempts will be made to contact you. After three attempts have been made the shipping company will make arrangements to return your machine to our warehouse. Return shipping and a 10% restocking fee may apply. 

We cannot ship to P.O. or APO Boxes with internet orders. There are a couple of reasons for this. One is that many of our items are large and ship in boxes bigger than the post office will accept for postal boxes. Our on-line order system can’t determine what size of box your order will ship in. Another reason is that we ship items, like treadmill lubricant, that cannot be shipped through the US postal service. 

## Return Policy

We give a 30-day trial period on all products. If you receive a defective machine we will be happy to send a replacement machine or give a full refund. Returns for defective and non-defective products must be arranged within 30 days of receiving the product. If you are not satisfied for any reason please call 1-866-896-9777 to set up a return. Upon receiving a Return Authorization number, put your machine back in the box and take it to your curb to be picked up. We will send a freight carrier to pick up your machine and upon receipt at our warehouse we will refund the purchase price (price of machine and tax) less to and from shipping charges. If you receive a defective machine you will receive a replacement machine or a full refund. If you were not charged for shipping on your initial delivery you will only be charged for the return shipping fee. A 10% restocking fee is also charged on all returned or canceled merchandise (unless the merchandise is defective). If your product(s) has shipped (even if you have not received your machine) return shipping and restocking fees will apply 

All products must be returned in good condition, and with all paperwork, parts and accessories or an additional 10% charge may be added. You can expect a refund in the same form of payment originally used for purchase within 30 days of our receiving your returned product.
